governing.com 2014-06-29

# Privacy Policy for e.Republic, Inc.

## Privacy Policy & Terms for e.Republic

_Last Updated September 5, 2013_

e.Republic, Inc. is the nation’s leading publishing, research, event and new media company focused on the state and local government and education markets. Serving both government and industry for over 25 years, e.Republic publishes the market’s leading periodicals and websites, runs the largest intergovernmental conferences in the nation and produces over 100 targeted and custom events annually. Information about e.Republic and its products and services can be obtained at [www.erepublic.com](http://www.erepublic.com/).

e.Republic is comprised of the following brands:

  1. Government Technology
  2. Government Technology Events
  3. Center for Digital Government / Center for Digital Education 
  4. GOVERNING
  5. GOVERNING Institute
  6. Emergency Management
  7. Public CIO
  8. Digital Communitites
  9. GovTech Exchange
  10. GOVERNING Exchange
  11. Navigator
  12. Industry Insider
  13. FutureStructure

## Terms and Conditions

e.Republic owns and operates several public-facing websites, including, but not limited to erepublic.com, governing.com, govtech.com, emergencymgmt.com, digitalcommunities.com, futurestructure.com, and centerdigitaled.com (collectively, the "Sites and Services"). We operate several registration-based private sites, including, but not limited to governmentnavigator.com, governingexchange.com, education-exchange.net, govtechexchange.com, groups.digitalcommunities.com and tools.erepublic.com (collectively, the "Services").

Your use of the Sites and Services and associated products, regardless of media, is subject to the terms, conditions, and disclaimers set forth below; to the Privacy Policy herein; and to all applicable laws and regulations. In addition, e.Republic reserves the right to terminate access to the Sites and Services for any reason, and to take any other actions that e.Republic, in its sole discretion, believes to be in the interest of the company and some or all of its users and customers. e.Republic reserves the right to modify these disclaimers, terms, and conditions of access, without advance notice.

This is a binding contract between e.Republic and you. By accessing our Sites and Services, you hereby accept this agreement. As a material condition of such use, you warrant that you are over the age of eighteen and that you have provided accurate and complete information in any communication with e.Republic.

In using our Sites and Services you are deemed to have read and agreed to the following terms and conditions:

The following terminology applies to these Terms and Conditions, Privacy Statement and Disclaimer Notice and any or all Agreements: "Client", "You" and "Your" refers to you, the person accessing our Sites and Services and accepting the Company's terms and conditions. "The Company", "Ourselves", "We" and "Us", refers to our Company. "Party", "Parties", or "Us", refers to both the Client and ourselves, or either the Client or ourselves. All terms refer to the offer, acceptance and consideration of payment necessary to undertake the process of our assistance to the Client in the most appropriate manner, whether by formal meetings of a fixed duration, or any other means, for the express purpose of meeting the Client's needs in respect of provision of the Company's stated services/products, in accordance with and subject to, prevailing United States Law. Any use of the above terminology or other words in the singular, plural, capitalisation and/or he/she or they, are taken as interchangeable and therefore as referring to same.

## Exclusions and Limitations

The information on our Sites and Services is provided on an "as is" basis. To the fullest extent permitted by law, this Company: 

  * excludes all representations and warranties relating to our Sites and Services and its contents or which is or may be provided by any affiliates or any other third party, including in relation to any inaccuracies or omissions in our Sites and Services and/or the Company's literature; and 
  * excludes all liability for damages arising out of or in connection with your use of our Sites and Services. This includes, without limitation, direct loss, loss of business or profits (whether or not the loss of such profits was foreseeable, arose in the normal course of things or you have advised this Company of the possibility of such potential loss), damage caused to your computer, computer software, systems and programs and the data thereon or any other direct or indirect, consequential and incidental damages. This Company does not however exclude liability for death or personal injury caused by its negligence. The above exclusions and limitations apply only to the extent permitted by law. None of your statutory rights as a consumer are affected. 

## Availability 

Redistribution or republication of any part of this site or its content is prohibited, including such by framing or other similar or any other means, without the express written consent of the Company. The Company does not warrant that the service from this site will be uninterrupted, timely or error free, although it is provided to the best ability. By using our Sites and Services you thereby indemnify this Company, its employees, agents and affiliates against any loss or damage, in whatever manner, howsoever caused. 

## Links from our Sites and Services 

We do not monitor or review the content of other party's websites which are linked to from our Sites and Services. Opinions expressed or material appearing on such websites are not necessarily shared or endorsed by us and should not be regarded as the publisher of such opinions or material. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices, or content, of these sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site & to read the privacy statements of these sites. You should evaluate the security and trustworthiness of any other site connected to this site or accessed through this site yourself, before disclosing any personal information to them. This Company will not accept any responsibility for any loss or damage in whatever manner, howsoever caused, resulting from your disclosure to third parties of personal information. 

## Use Limitation

Our Services are intended for your business use only. Access to and use of any Service is through a combination of a user name and password. e.Republic authorizes you to view a single copy of the material on the Site solely for your use or use by authorized additional recipients. Materials from the Service are intended for the exclusive use by you at the location(s) specified in your subscription. You agree that such access will not be shared with others. You may not access any Service using the name or password of any other party. Unauthorized access to any Service, or to the telecommunications or computer facilities used to deliver such Service, is a material breach of this Agreement and may be a violation of law. You assume all responsibility for any claim, demand or damage resulting from another party obtaining your password. You shall not attempt to modify, decompile, reverse engineer or otherwise attempt to gain access to any technology or source code underlying any Service. By using any Service you represent and warrant that you are (a) authorized to form legally binding contracts under applicable law and that the information you provide is accurate, current and complete and (b) not a minor. We reserve the right at our sole discretion to refuse any Service to anyone at any time. 

Any authorized additional recipients of materials from the Services are also subject to this Agreement. You agree to take full responsibility for any additional recipients for agreeing to and following these Terms and Conditions.

Our Services do not guarantee the quality, legality, truth or accuracy of the listings and/or Services. Our Services disclaims any responsibility for system downtime which may affect the timely submissions of content. You agree to accept periodic email notices from us explaining our new Services. You assume all risks associated with dealing with other users with whom you come in contact through the Services. Because user authentication on the Internet is difficult, Our Services cannot and does not confirm that each user is who they claim to be. In the event that you have a dispute with another user, you hereby release Our Services, its subsidiaries, affiliates, directors, officers, employees and agents from and against any and all claims, demands and damages (actual and consequential) of every kind and nature, known and unknown, suspected and unsuspected, disclosed and undisclosed, arising out of or in any way connected with such disputes. If you are a California resident, you waive California Civil Code § 1542, which states, "A general release does not extend to claims which the creditor does not know or suspect to exist in his favor at the time of executing the release, which if known by him must have materially affected his settlement with the debtor." You agree to indemnify and hold Our Services and its subsidiaries, affiliates, officers, directors, agents, and employees, harmless from any claim or demand, including reasonable attorneys' fees, made by any third party due to or arising out of your breach of this Agreement or the documents incorporated by reference, or your violation of any law or the rights of a third party. We do not control the information provided by other users which is made available through our Site. You may find other user's information to be offensive, harmful, inaccurate or deceptive. Please use caution, common sense, and practice safe trading when using our Site. Please note that there are also risks of dealing with foreign nationals, underage persons or people acting under false pretense.

## User Conduct and Behavior

When you use any Services or the Site, you represent, warrant and agree that you will not:  
(A) falsify or misrepresent any personal or business information regarding your identity or intentions with respect to any matter;  
(B) post, publish, transmit, distribute, or upload any information through or link directly or indirectly any information to the Site that Our Services, in its sole discretion, deems unlawful, obscene, derogatory, abusive, threatening, discriminatory with respect to race or gender, or is otherwise disagreeable;  
(C) post, publish, transmit, distribute, or upload any information through or link directly or indirectly any information to the Site that contains a virus, Trojan horse, worms, time bombs, cancelbots, or any other harmful software code or programming routine that are intended to damage, detrimentally interfere with, surreptitiously intercept or expropriate any system, data or personal information;  
(D) post, publish, transmit, distribute, or upload any information through or link directly or indirectly any information to the Site that is unlawful, fraudulent, or otherwise disagreeable, including without limitation, any information, communication or transmission that constitutes or supports the commission of any illegal activity or any violation of local, state, national or foreign law, statute, ordinance or regulation (including without limitation, those governing export control, consumer protection, unfair competition, anti-discrimination or false advertising);  
(E) post, publish, transmit, distribute, or upload any information through or link directly or indirectly any information to the Site that violates any copyright, trademark or any other proprietary intellectual property rights of others, unless you have obtained permission from such owner and such action would not violate any of the above rights in such property;  
(F) post, publish, transmit, distribute, or upload through or link directly or indirectly any information to the Site any bulk e-mail solicitations, chain letters, solicitations, advertisements, pyramid schemes or any other unsolicited communication, including without limitation, spamming Our Services's users;  
(G) use, reproduce, distribute, publish or communicate any information obtained from the Site, for any commercial reason, unless such activity has been expressly approved in writing by Our Services; or  
(H) use any robot, spider, other automatic device, or manual process to monitor or copy Our Services's web pages or content contained herein;  
(I) use any device, software or routine to bypass Our Services's robot exclusion headers or meta tags, or to interfere or attempt to interfere with the proper working of the Site or any transaction being communicated or conducted on the Site, or take any action that imposes an unreasonable or disproportionately large load on Our Services's infrastructure; or  
(J) create liability for Our Services or cause Our Services to lose (in whole or in part) the services of Our Services's ISPs or other suppliers. Our Services reserves the right, in its sole discretion, to amend, edit, remove or otherwise block any material posted by you which may violate any state, federal or local law or violate any aspect of this Agreement, or which Our Services, in its sole discretion, deems unlawful, obscene, derogatory, abusive, threatening, discriminatory with respect to race or gender, or otherwise disagreeable. 

However, Our Services does not assume responsibility for reviewing or verifying the material, content and information on its Site and is not responsible for any damages, losses, expenses or other injuries incurred by you or any other user as a result of relying on any material, content and information posted on the Site.

## Fees and Financial Obligations

You agree to pay the fees and accept the payment policies for each Service for which you are registered. In the event your account becomes past due, your Service may be suspended, the remaining balance will be considered in default, and the entire account balance will become due and owing immediately. You also agree to pay all reasonable collection costs, including attorneys' fees. 

## Copyright Notice 

Copyright and other relevant intellectual property rights exists on all text relating to the Company's services and the full content of our Sites and Services. 

## Force Majeure

Neither party shall be liable to the other for any failure to perform any obligation under any Agreement which is due to an event beyond the control of such party including but not limited to any Act of God, terrorism, war, Political insurgence, insurrection, riot, civil unrest, act of civil or military authority, uprising, earthquake, flood or any other natural or man made eventuality outside of our control, which causes the termination of an agreement or contract entered into, nor which could have been reasonably foreseen. Any Party affected by such event shall forthwith inform the other Party of the same and shall use all reasonable endeavours to comply with the terms and conditions of any Agreement contained herein. 

## Waiver

Failure of either Party to insist upon strict performance of any provision of this or any Agreement or the failure of either Party to exercise any right or remedy to which it, he or they are entitled hereunder shall not constitute a waiver thereof and shall not cause a diminution of the obligations under this or any Agreement. No waiver of any of the provisions of this or any Agreement shall be effective unless it is expressly stated to be such and signed by both Parties. 

## General

The laws of the United States govern these terms and conditions. By accessing our Sites and Services you consent to these terms and conditions and to the exclusive jurisdiction of the United States courts in all disputes arising out of such access. If any of these terms are deemed invalid or unenforceable for any reason (including, but not limited to the exclusions and limitations set out above), then the invalid or unenforceable provision will be severed from these terms and the remaining terms will continue to apply. Failure of the Company to enforce any of the provisions set out in these Terms and Conditions and any Agreement, or failure to exercise any option to terminate, shall not be construed as waiver of such provisions and shall not affect the validity of these Terms and Conditions or of any Agreement or any part thereof, or the right thereafter to enforce each and every provision. These Terms and Conditions shall not be amended, modified, varied or supplemented except in writing and signed by duly authorised representatives of the Company. 

## Our overall privacy statement

We believe personal privacy is a serious issue. Because we gather certain types of information about the users of our web sites, job network, subscribers to our magazines or attendees of events we organize, we think it is important that you understand the terms and conditions surrounding the collection and use of that information. This privacy statement discloses the types of information we gather and how we use it. These privacy practices apply to the Web site that you were viewing when you clicked through to this policy, as well as all other e.Republic Inc. sites and activities.

We believe you should understand what personally identifiable information we collect when you visit our web sites, how we gather this information, how this information is used, instances when this information is shared and what choices are available to users regarding the collection, use and distribution of data. This statement also outlines what security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under e.Republic's control.

## What information does e.Republic collect?

Our primary goal in collecting personal information is to provide you with the best and most useful content and services. Several of the services and features that we offer on our web sites require you to provide us with information as a condition of usage. These include the ability to post opinions or other content, participation in sweepstakes or contests, subscriptions to print magazines and email newsletters, access to sponsored parts of our site and participation in any job boards and databases we may establish.

We collect personally identifiable information, such as your name, email address, postal address, phone number and credit card information when you provide it to us. We may also collect your social media IDs if you use them to leave comments or participate in our online communities. From time to time, we may also collect other sensitive information such as your job title and job function.

Once you register using a form on one of our web sites you are no longer anonymous to us.

## How does e.Republic use cookies?

Your Internet browser has a feature called cookies, which store small amounts of data on your computer about your visit to any of our sites. You do not need to have cookies turned on to visit most of our sites, although active participation in certain areas of our sites may require cookies. Cookies alone tell us nothing about who you are unless you specifically give us personally identifiable information, in which case we use the information to enhance your services in the ways described below. By adjusting your settings on your browser, you may elect not to allow cookies to be collected.

We also use technologies, including electronic images known as Web bugs—sometimes called transparent GIFs, clear GIFs, or beacons—that allow us to track general user-traffic patterns. We also automatically receive and record information from our servers and from your browser, including your IP address, the time of your visit to pages on our site, and information about pages you visited. Unless you have registered for one of our products or services, the information we gather through the use of tracking technologies cannot be matched with any personally identifiable information about you.

We use cookies and tracking technologies in a variety of ways, including:

  1. Keeping count of return visits to our site or our advertisers' or partners' sites; 
  2. Accumulating and reporting anonymous, aggregate (data collected in mass), statistical information on Web-site and advertisement usage; 
  3. Determining which features our overall user population likes best; 
  4. Saving your password or registration data so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit our sites; 
  5. Displaying the most appropriate advertising or content based on your interests.

We allow other companies that are presenting advertisements on our sites and, sometimes, in our newsletters to use tracking technology on your computer. We do not give any personally identifiable information to them as part of this relationship. Unless you visit the Web site of these companies and provide them with personally identifiable information about yourself, these tracking technologies tell those advertisers nothing about who you are. Our advertisers' use of tracking technology is subject to their own privacy policies.

## How does e.Republic use this information?

We use the information we gather for four general purposes:

  1. To customize the advertising and the content you see; 
  2. To enhance the user experience on our sites. We use tracking information to determine how well each page performs overall based on aggregate user demographics and traffic patterns to those pages. This helps us continue to build a better service for you; 
  3. To fulfill your requests for certain products and services, such as sending out electronic newsletters and enabling you to participate in paid services and contests; 
  4. To send you information you agreed to receive about topics we think will be of interest to you.

## Does e.Republic share this information?

For personally identifiable information you provide to us:

We will make your personally identifiable information available to other companies or people when:

  1. You have elected to allow us to share that information at the time that you registered with us or provided us the information, or through a subsequent opt in or affirmative election through our web site. 
  2. You volunteer information or create a public profile in the course of your participation in our community features such as forums, user opinions and comments, and other forms of public communication and interaction. 
  3. You use cobranded services (i.e., sites or services that we offer to you in connection with a partner that is identified on the site). When you use a cobranded service within our network of sites, you grant us permission to pass your registration information and applicable survey responses back to that service partner. Their use of your information is subject to their applicable privacy policies. We hire third-party vendors to provide specialized services such as customer support; email message deployment; suppression, merge and de-duplication services; data processing; and special products or services that you have requested. These companies are only allowed to use the information in order to help us fulfill our services to you. These third parties may not use that information for any purpose other than assisting us in providing those products and services.
  4. You unsubscribe for a mailing that we send to you on behalf of a third party. We may share your removal instruction with the third party so that it may be added to that party's list of people to whom they may not send emails. 
  5. You are the winner of a contest or a sweepstakes that is co-sponsored with a third party and that third party needs your information in order to manage the prize fulfillment process. 
  6. When required by law, such as when we respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process. 
  7. We believe that your actions violate applicable laws, e.Republic Terms of Use, or any usage guidelines for specific products or services, or threaten the rights, property, or safety of our company, our users, or others.

## Magazine subscriptions

Visitors to our Web site are invited to subscribe to our various hard-copy magazines and e-mail newsletter services. Hard-copy subscribers are asked to include their email address, which is used for internal informational and promotional purposes only.

We hire third-party vendors to handle subscription fulfillment. These companies are only allowed to use the information in order to help us fulfill our services to you. These third parties may not use that information for any purpose other than assisting us in providing those products and services.

## Job Network

Registration on this site is voluntary, and is designed for the purpose of seeking employment. Upon registration the site collects your email address and other personal information (such as employment skills) in a "profile." The site collects personal and demographic information you choose to provide us. 

When you apply for a position, however, you need to provide your name and full contact information; this information is shared only with the employer to whom you applied. However, if you maintain a resume as part of your profile, the information in this resume may be viewed by employers other than those to whom you have specifically applied. In order to provide you with the broadest exposure to potential employment opportunities, information you place in your profile may be shared with our partner, RealMatch, its affiliated companies or within other sites powered by RealMatch. Neither RealMatch nor its affiliates distributes personal information for advertising purposes.

RealMatch attempts to limit access to the searchable resume database only to potential employers, recruiters, hiring managers, headhunters, and human resource professionals. However, WE DO NOT AND CAN NOT guarantee that other parties (including parties disguised as employers) will not gain access to this database. Therefore, RealMatch and e.Republic hereby specifically exclude any responsibility and or liability related to the use made of resumes by third parties who access such resumes while they are in our searchable database.

RealMatch and e.Republic may use your information to contact you about new products or services offered by RealMatch, e.Republic or RealMatch-affiliated sites. Any feedback that you provide may be used for marketing purposes or to improve our services. If you apply for a position on this site, you may be asked to provide information, such as answers to qualifying questions, or answers regarding your gender, race or other protected status where permitted by applicable law. RealMatch or e.Republic are not responsible for any information you choose to supply to third parties. You are encouraged to check and evaluate carefully and diligently every job ad to which you choose to apply and submit your information.

RealMatch and e.Republic share your information with third parties who help us in the delivery of our own products and services to you. These third parties may not use that information for any purpose other than assisting us in providing those products and services.

RealMatch and e.Republic may also present job advertisements from external affiliated recruitment advertising companies ("External Source") to enrich the content for all TheJobNetwork users. If you decide to apply to such external job advertisements, you acknowledge that subject to your consent (opting in by clicking the applicable box during the application process), RealMatch will transfer all necessary information required by such External Source with respect to your candidacy to the respective job advertisement. If you do not wish us to transfer such information please refrain from opting in online. RealMatch and/or e.Republic are not responsible and shall not be held liable for any content provided on/by such External Sources and/or privacy practices or use of your information of/by such External Sources. We recommend that you visit the applicable sites/boards for information regarding such External Source's privacy practices.

Subject to your consent, we may use your information to contact you about other products or services available from our affiliates.

Subject to your consent, we may also share your information with third parties who may contact you about their products or services.

TheJobNetwork Sites are not intended for users under 18 years of age. We do not intentionally gather personal information from children under 18.

## Logging traffic data

In order to better service the needs of those who visit our site, we use third parties to collect certain traffic data and may include the use of cookies or web beacons to colelct this data. These include the platform you are using (such as a Macintosh or PC), browser type (such as Chrome, Firefox or Microsoft Internet Explorer), IP address (or Internet Protocol address, which identifies your service provider, but not you personally) and the previous URL (Uniform Resource Location, or Web address) visited by you before clicking through to our website. None of these disclose personal information about you, and what information they do reveal is used exclusively for internal administration purposes.

We monitor aggregate visitor activity on our sites and share this information with our advertisers, but at no stage are you personally identifiable, nor is any personal information about you divulged.

## Google Analytics and Display Advertising

We have updated our Google Analytics tracking code to support Google Display Advertising through the Remarketing feature. This enables Google Analytics to collect data about your traffic via the DoubleClick cookie in addition to data collected through the standard Google Analytics implementation. Display Advertising lets us enable features in Analytics that aren’t available through standard implementations.

The Remarketing feature allows third-party vendors, including Google, to show your ads on sites across the Internet. In this regard, wWe as well as third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies together to inform, optimize, and serve ads based on someone's past visits to your website.

You can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads using the Ads Preferences Manager available here.

## Special events

e.Republic Inc. is also involved in the business of organizing and staging conferences and may, from time to time, use the Web to promote these events, sell conference subscriptions and invite prospective attendees to supply certain information about themselves. This demographic data may then be used for pre- or post-conference marketing and could be shared with our event co-sponsors, but will not be disclosed to any other outside third parties without the consent of the individual or organization concerned. e.Republic will also prevail upon these co-sponsors to respect the privacy of those who entrust information to us.

## Order forms

e.Republic also makes use of the Web to promote research papers and research services offered by any of its subsidiary or associate companies, including the Center for Digital Government or Center for Digital Education. These products and services may be downloaded or purchased online, at which point various personal information is requested. Other than financial data, this information may be shared with the company underwriting the document or research.

Conference attendees are asked to supply certain personal information, including name, contact information and credit card number. The contact information is used for communicating with you regarding the conference, while your billing information will only be used to bill you for that service. Other than the financial data, this information might be shared with our event co-sponsors, but will not be disclosed to any other outside third parties without the consent of the individual or organization concerned. Again, e.Republic urges these co-sponsors to respect the privacy of those who entrust information to us.

## Security

When you place an order online, we scramble your personal information and credit card information using SSL encryption technology before any information is sent over the Internet. This makes it virtually impossible for your information to be stolen or intercepted while being transferred across the Internet. When we receive your order, it is encrypted until we are ready to process it. Once the order is processed we erase your credit card information from our Web site.

## What if I don’t want to give personal information?

Users who would rather not provide any of the user data requested by any of our registration or subscription processes do not need to register with us or to subscribe. You can still view much of the content and use many of the services offered by our sites without registering. Opting not to provide certain personal information when requested means that you may not be able to access some areas of our web site.

## Changes to this Web Site Privacy Statment

If we decide to change this Web Site Privacy Statement, we will post the revised policy at this location, so that users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use Personal Information in a manner that is substantially different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will seek to notify users by way of an email.  

## Contact Information  

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at info@erepublic.com.

e.Republic, Inc.  
100 Blue Ravine Road  
Folsom, CA 95630  
916-932-1300
